<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Regenbogenpony]]></title>
  <link href="http://rainbowda.sh/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rainbowda.sh/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-11T21:02:12+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://rainbowda.sh/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[map]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FILDI]]></title>
    <link href="http://rainbowda.sh/fildi/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T15:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://rainbowda.sh/fildi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Das. Tausend Mal das:</p>

<center><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/RYlCVwxoL_g" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center>


<p>Transkript:</p>

<p>Don't call it a comb-back, I have hair for years.</p>

<p>I'm scared.</p>

<p>I'm scared that my abilities are gone.</p>

<p>I'm scared that I'm gonna fuck this up.</p>

<p>And I'm scared of you.</p>

<p>I don't wanna start. But I will.</p>

<p>This is an invocation for everyone who hasn't begun. Who's stuck in a terrible place between zero and one.</p>

<p>Let me realize that my past failures at follow-through are no indication of my future performance, they are just healthy little fires that are gonna warm up my ass.</p>

<p>If my FILDI is strong, let me keep him in a velvet box until I really really need him. If my FILDI is weak, let me feed him oranges and not let him gorge himself on ego and arrogance.</p>

<p>Let me not hit on my Facebook, like it's a crack pipe. Keep the browser closed.</p>

<p>If I catch myself wearing a tutu - too fat, too late, too old - let me shake it off like a donkey would shake off something it doesn't like.</p>

<p>And when I get that feeling in my stomach - you know the feeling when all of a sudden you get a ball of energy and it shoots down into your legs and up into your arms and tells you to get up and stand up and go to the refrigerator and get a cheese sandwich? That's my cheesemonster talking. And my cheesemonster will never be satisfied by Cheddar. Only the cheese of accomplishment.</p>

<p>Let me think about the people who I care about the most. And how, when they fail or disappoint me, I still love them, I still give them chances and I still see the best in them. Let me extend that generosity to myself.</p>

<p>Let me find and use metaphors to help me understand the world around me and give me the strength to get rid of them when it's apparent  they no longer work.</p>

<p>Let me thank the parts of me that I no don't understand or are outside of my rational control, like my creativity and my courage. And let me remember that my courage is a wild dog. It won't just come when I call it. I have to chase it down and hold on as tight as I can.</p>

<p>Let me not be so vain to think that I'm the sole author of my victories and a victim of my defeats.</p>

<p>Let me remember that the unintended meaning that people project onto what I do is neither my fault nor something I can take credit for.</p>

<p>Perfectionism may look good in his shiny shoes, but he's a little bit of an asshole and no one invites him to their pool-parties.</p>

<p>Let me remember that the impact of criticism is often not the intent of the critic. But when the intent is evil - that's what the block-button's for.</p>

<p>And when I eat my critique, let me be able to separate out the good advice from the bitter herbs.</p>

<p>???</p>

<p>Let me not think about my work only as a stepping stone to something else. And if it is - let me become fascinated with the shape of the stone.</p>

<p>Let me take the idea that has gotten me this far and put it to bed. What I'm about to do will not be that. But it will be something.</p>

<p>There's no need to sharpen my pencils any more. My pencils are sharp enough. Even the dull ones will make a mark.</p>

<p>Warts and all. Let's start this shit up.</p>

<p>(And god, let me enjoy this. Life isn't just a sequence of waiting for things to be done.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Dingsdacy]]></title>
    <link href="http://rainbowda.sh/postprivacy/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-31T20:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://rainbowda.sh/postprivacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Meinungen sind scheisse</h3>

<p>Es gibt so Themen, da mache ich mir diffuse Gedanken zu, sage dann auch öffentlich was zu und habe trotzdem keine feste Meinung. Was ich im übrigen sowieso für einen besseren Zustand halte, als Meinungen zu verfestigen. Meinungen sind nämlich scheisse. Aber das nur nebenbei. Martin hat also irgendwas gesagt woran er sich sowieso schon kaum erinnert und dann kommt aus dem Internet plötzlich: <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='“Du bist doch einer von diesen Post-Privacy Spacken. Erklär dich doch mal!”'>“Du bist doch einer von diesen Post-Privacy Spacken. Erklär dich doch mal!”</span> Jetzt kann und will ich aber keine länglichen Essays mit zwanzig Focault-Zitaten schreiben und auch das Lesen ebenjener strengt mich eher an. Trotzdem sei hier mal festgehalten warum ich eine Diskussion die manchmal auch unter dem Stichpunkt "Post-Privacy" geführt (oder eben nicht geführt) wird, für wichtig halte.</p>

<h3>We lost the war</h3>

<center><iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/sAb7X5au-l8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center>


<p>Eine wesentliche Klimaveränderung ist nicht mehr zu verhindern. Genausowenig wie der zunehmende Verlust der Privatsphäre - darin scheint man sich scheinbar mittlerweile einig zu sein. Zu verhindern wäre beides nur durch Regulation, die die Mehrheit der Menschen zwingen würde grundlegend anders zu handeln. Das halte ich für naiv und donquichottisch.</p>

<p>Wer hier seine Rocinante satteln möchte, dem sei das unbenommen. Das damit schlecht trennbar verbundene Selbstbild des Helden im Kampf mit Spacken, Pöbel und Kommerz ist verständlich wie bedauerlich.</p>

<p>Was aber nun wenn die Polkappen der Privatsphäre in zehn Jahren eisfrei sind? Wenn der heroische Kampf nun doch verloren wird?</p>

<h3>Chancen und Risken</h3>

<p>Selbst noch Einordnung der Zukunft nach Chancen und Risken vorzunehmen halte ich für zweitrangig. Dystopien gibt es ausreichend, Utopien mittlerweile auch. Was ich interessant finde sind Strategien das Eine zu vermeiden und das Andere zu fördern. Von selbst werden Dinge in der Regel vor allem anders, nicht zwingend schlechter oder besser.</p>

<p>Und hier ist der Punkt an dem ich bisher nicht weiterkomme, und auch noch keine wirklich befriedigenden Perspektiven gefunden habe. Dieses - vorallem das eigene - Versagen frustriert mich sehr.</p>

<p>Ich spreche gerne über Dinge die mich bewegen. Die mich ausmachen. Und doch kann ich über viele wesentliche Aspekte meinerselbst nicht öffentlich reden. Weil Andere dadurch Ziele von Diskriminierung werden würden. Oder ich selbst, das ist aber nur Feigheit. Ich hätte gerade für Erstes - weil es für mich nicht kontrollierbar und bewältigbar ist - gerne eine Strategie. Bevor uns das Wasser bis zum Hals steht.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
